

Nelson Nunes

Senior Software Developer Cape Town, South Africa

If you are looking for a dynamic, enthusiastic team player with a keen eye for advancement and improvements in the tech industry then I am confident I would be an excellent fit for your company. My programming career began simply because of my hate of computers, however, I have developed a strong connection to all things tech related over the last 25 years of my career. I am a solutionist who enjoys unpacking problems and working on the best way to resolve it, ultimately providing the client with the simplest solution in advancement. During a break in my academic studies, I endeavoured to understand computers a bit more with a C & C++ programming course. This is where my passion for programming and code began, the impression of the screen being an empty canvas and the code being a brush fuelled my passion for this career. I was fortunate enough to work for well-known international companies early in my career, and advanced my skills in various studies as I believe selfimprovement is critical. After 14 years in the industry I found myself unemployed and fell on hard times. I set off on an entrepreneurial mission, during this time I took on a few personal projects whilst studying part-time. Entrepreneurship is no walk in the park, and I made the decision to seek employment on a full-time basis, this would also allow me to develop myself more and stay in touch with the continual advancements this fast-paced environment. My time is spent being the best dad I can to my young daughter, developing myself and staying in touch with tech news, and reaching my unofficial goal of being a 1% top listener on Spotify. Thank you for your time in reviewing my portfolio and I hope to hear from you soon. Nelson.

Experience

Senior Software Developer iOCO

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Nov 2019 - Dec 2022

Senior Software Developer Capricorn Bank

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Nov 2021 - Oct 2022

Senior Software Developer (Team Lead) Vodacom

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote)
May 2021 - Oct 2021

Senior Software Developer AngloAmerican

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Jan 2021 - Apr 2021

Senior Software Developer Sanlam

Cape Town, South Africa (Fully Remote) Nov 2019 - Dec 2020

Education

University of Stellenbosh

Certificate

2022 - 2022

Business and System Analysis

Udemy

Certificate

2020 - 2020

Master ASP.NET MVC Core 3.1

Udemy

Certificate

2020 - 2020

Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer

Udemy

Certificate

2020 - 2020

RESTful Web services with ASP.NET Core

Udemy

Certificate

2019 - 2019

React - The Complete Guide (incl. Hooks, React Router, Redux)

Entrepreneur

Oteka

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Uber Driver/Partner

UBER

Johannesburg, South Africa
Oct 2016 - Oct 2018
1663 trips completed.
One of the highest rated Uber Drivers in South Africa, with a rating of 4.9

Entrepreneur

Oteka

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Apr 2014 - Sep 2016

Senior Solutions Developer/Consultant

Asyst International

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Oct 2012 - Mar 2014

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Jan 2011 - Sep 2012

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes (UK)

Johannesburg, South Africa (Fully Remote) Feb 2010 - Dec 2011

Senior Software Developer

Alexander Forbes

Johannesburg, South Africa (Hybrid) Jan 2008 - Jan 2010

Intermediate Software Developer

Dimension Data

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 2005 - Dec 2007

Software Developer

The Workforce Group

Johannesburg, South Africa Oct 1999 - Sep 2005

Skills

.NET Framework (C#)
.NET Core (C#)

Amazon DynamoDB

Angular

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2012 - 2012 SCRUM

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2010 - 2010 ITIL 3.0

Alexander Forbes

Certificate

2010 - 2010 COBIT 5.0

Microsoft

Certificate

2000 - 2000

MVP - Visual Basic 6.0

Boston City Campus

Certificate

1999 - 1999

C & C++ Programming

West Ridge High School

Matric

1991 - 1996

Contact

nelson@nelsonunes.dev +27 65 889 6633 Cape Town, South Africa

https://github.com/nelsonunes-dev

ASP.NET (C#)

AWS

Azure

CSS/Bootstrap

JavaScript

Microsoft SQL Server

MongoDB

MySQL

NodeJS

PostgreSQL

React

Typescript

Xamarin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nelsonunes/

https://nelsonunes.dev